linkresearchtools.com 2016-03-27

# 

Privacy Statement
As of January 2015

1. Data protection and legal notice
We from LinkResearchTools are committed to protect your privacy. The provisions from this
Privacy Statement apply to all of our websites and tools. They shall settle details regarding
data collection and processing, and the usage of your data. By using our websites or tools,
you accept these data protection provisions with all its regulations and terms. If you do not
agree with any of the terms and conditions stipulated in this Privacy Statement, do not use
our websites and/or our tools.
2. Provider und media owner
Owner, publisher and editor:
LinkResearchTools GmbH
Leonard-Bernstein-Strasse 10/ Floor 7
Saturn Tower
1220 Vienna, Austria, Europe
www.linkresearchtools.de
www.linkresearchtools.com
Phone AT: +43 720 116 440
Phone US: +1 (866) 347-3660
Phone UK: +44 800 011 9736
E-mail: feedback@linkresearchtools.com
Link Detox
Recover – Protect – Build
http://www.linkdetox.com
Further information
http://www.linkresearchtools.com/helptext/
http://help.linkdetox.com/
                                                                        LinkResearchTools 1

3. Legal basis
The Austrian Data Protection Act 2000 (Datenschutzgesetz 2000, DSG 2000) form the legal
basis for this Privacy Statement. Further information about the Austrian Data Protection Act
can be found under the following link:
http://www.ris.bka.gv.at/GeltendeFassung.wxe?Abfrage=Bundesnormen&Gesetzesnummer
=10001597
4. Contact us
Please contact us if you have questions concerning this Privacy Statement or concerning the
handling personal data. Please send an e-mail to feedback@linkresearchtools.com or a letter
to LinkResearchTools GmbH, Leonard-Bernstein-Strasse 10/ Floor 7, Saturn Tower, 1220
Vienna, Austria, Europe.
5. Usage of our websites and tools
Or websites and tools allow users to learn more about our company, download content and
provide us with contact details and other demographic information.
This information is saved on the servers of our software partner HubSpot. We shall be entitled
to use this information to establish contact with the visitors of our website(s), and to
determine which of our company products and services are relevant to our visitors. Any and
all information collected shall be subject to the provisions of this Privacy Statement. We
undertake to use the information collected exclusively for marketing purposes and/or lead
generation.
HubSpot is a software company based in the U.S., with a branch office in Ireland. Contact
details: HubSpot, 2nd Floor 30 North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland, Phone: +353 1 5187500.
HubSpot is subject to the TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal and the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and
the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework.
                                                                        LinkResearchTools 2

6. Information we collect
6.1.    Visits to our websites
You can visit our website(s) without providing any personal data. Proving personal data is only
required in case you wish to use our tools. Other than that, we collect navigation information.
6.2.    Personal data
Personal data is data which you choose to give us voluntarily that identifies you as a person.
Such data may in particular include contact details such as e.g. name, e-mail address,
company name, address, phone number, etc. Personal data may also include information
about you that is available to the public on the Internet, comprising in particular information
on Facebook, LinkedIn, Xing, Twitter und Google. Such information may also be included to
our work.
6.3.    Navigation information
Navigation information includes data about your device and your visit to our website(s)
and/or the usage of our tools, including in particular information about your IP-address,
location, the browser type you use, referral source, duration of your visit and the pages you
opened.
6.4.    Privacy of children
Our website(s) have not been designed for children. We do not knowingly collect any personal
data from children under 18. Please contact us if you suspect data has been collected from
minors. We will remove such data immediately.
                                                                          LinkResearchTools 3

7. Usage of collected information
7.1.     Compliance with data protection provisions
We undertake to use any and all data collected only in strict compliance with the provisions
stipulated in this Privacy Statement.
7.2.     Refrain from selling data
We undertake to refrain from selling personal data to third parties.
7.3.     Usage of personal data
In addition to further types of usage stipulated in this Privacy Statement, we use personal
data to:
a.) improve your browser usage by personalizing the websites.
b.) send you marketing material regarding our company.
c.) to improve our free and payable offers (information and articles that cannot be accessed
openly such as e.g. white papers, training courses or special seminars).
7.4.     Usage of navigation information
We use navigation information to improve the websites and our tools. We use navigation
information alone or in combination with personal data to offer and to send you personalized
information regarding our company.
7.5.     Usage of information on the usage of our tools
We use statistics showing how the different features of our tools are used. This helps us
develop our tools with a greater focus on user needs.
7.6.     Service provider
We reserve the right to hire third parties (e.g. web agencies) to provide us with services for
the visitors of our website(s) and/or users of our tools. We undertake to ensure that such
service providers comply with our Privacy Statement.
7.7.     Security of personal data
We use secure technologies and procedures to protect personal data from unauthorized
access. Personal data is stored on secure servers situated in safe and surveilled environments.
                                                                           LinkResearchTools 4

7.8.     Social Media features
Our websites use Social Media features like “Facebook Share Buttons” and/or widgets like
“Share this”-Buttons or other widgets. Such features can register your IP-address and record
the page(s) you visited. They can also use cookies. Social Media features and widgets are
provided to our websites by third parties. This Privacy Statement does not apply to such
services. The terms of usage of the providers of such features are governed by their own
privacy policies.
7.9.     External websites
Our websites contain links to other websites. We shall not be obliged to verify foreign
websites, nor shall be held liable for any of the content or actions on foreign websites. Our
links to foreign websites do not allow any conclusions about whether or not we agree with
their content or whether or not we support their website owners. This Privacy Statement
does not apply to websites we link to.
7.10. Public forums
We offer publicly accessible forums and blogs that allow you to publish messages. Please keep
in mind that any and all information you publish on publicly accessible forums and blogs on
our websites may be registered and used by third parties. If you wish, we will edit or delete
any information you published on our websites. We reserve the right to delete posts that
contain offensive content or that are otherwise deemed inappropriate by us. Please find
details under Section 9. Unsubscribe.
7.11. Storage of personal data
We keep personal data for as long as we see a reasonable possibility that such data be used
for the purpose of establishing contact with regard to our subscription service. We delete
such information when no longer required, although we will delete such data sooner upon
request. Please find details under Section 9. Unsubscribe.
                                                                         LinkResearchTools 5

8. Navigation information
8.1.     Cookies
We use cookies to support you when browsing our website(s). A cookie is a small text file
stored on your device via a web server. Cookies cannot import viruses or run programs on
your device. One of the main reasons for using cookies is to improve your website usage by
helping you save time. Cookies will tell the web server that you have returned to a specific
page. This will retrieve the information previously provided, allowing you to use any
customized features again. You can chose to reject cookies. Most browsers accept cookies by
default, but you may change your browser settings to refuse cookies. If you do so, you may
not be able to use the full functionality of our website(s).
8.2.     Log Files
We may occasionally collect and combine demographic data such as your postal code, your
age, your gender and/or certain preferences via Log Files with your name or other personally
identifiable information. We may also register your hardware and/or software data, including
the following information: your IP-address, your browser type, the domain name, access
times and referring website addresses. We use this data to enhance the quality of our offers
and to create statistics about the usage of our website(s) and/or tools.
8.3.     Clear Gifs
We use a so-called Clear Gifs software that helps us improve our subscription service by
informing us which content is effective. Clear Gifs are small graphics with a unique identifier
(similar to cookies) that help analyze the user behavior of website visitors. In contrast to
cookies that are stored on a user’s device, Clear Gifs are invisibly embedded on websites and
in e-mails and are usually about the size of a pixel. We use Clear Gifs in our HTML-based e-
mails to see which e-mails were opened. We can thereby evaluate the effectiveness of
communication actions and marketing activities. We combine this information with personal
data. You can unsubscribe from such e-mails. Please find details under Section 9. Unsubscribe.
                                                                          LinkResearchTools 6

9.       Unsubscribe
9.1.     Check, correct and remove personal data
If you provide us with your personal data, you will have the following rights:
a.) You may check the user data you provided.
b.) You may correct mistakes, add missing data and/or correct data that has become
incorrect.
c.) You may request that your user data be not used for the purpose of establishing contact
with you.
d.) You may request to have your user data removed from each and every list.
e.) You may request to have your user data deleted.
If you wish to exercise your rights, please contact us under feedback@linkresearchtools.com
or send a letter to LinkResearchTools GmbH, Leonard-Bernstein-Strasse 10/ Floor 7, Saturn
Tower, 1220 Vienna, Austria, Europe.
Please include “Unsubscribe” in the subject. We will comply with your request as swiftly as
possible, and we will notify you as soon as it has been completed.
9.2.     Unsubscribe from our e-mail communications
You may unsubscribe from our e-mail communications at any time by clicking on the
“Unsubscribe” link at the end of the e-mail.
                                                                          LinkResearchTools 7

10.      Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google
Analytics uses cookies, text files that are stored on your device and that allow for analyzing
your website usage and behavior. The information about your website usage generated via
the cookie is usually transmitted to and stored by Google’s servers located in the United
States. On behalf of the website owner, Google will evaluate the information in order to
analyze your website behavior, to compile reports about the website activities and to render
further services to the website owner related to the website and Internet usage. The IP-
address transmitted from your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be associated with
any other data held by Google. You may reject the storage of cookies by selecting the
appropriate settings of your browser; please not, however, that in this case you may not be
able to use the full functionality of our websites. Furthermore, you can prevent the data
generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP-address)
from being transferred to and/or processed by Google, by downloading and installing the
following browser plugin:
https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en
11.      Disclaimer
We constantly review and update the content published on our websites. However, we do not
assume any liability or guarantee for the current relevance, correctness and/or completeness
of the information provided.
                                                                          LinkResearchTools 8
